<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Tim Post Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Tim Post Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://tinkertim.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Site! Again!]]></title>
        <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you
spend creating content on other people's platforms? I thought about it quite a
bit when it was touch-and-go if Twitter would stabilize again, and in all
fairness, that's still mostly the case.</p><p>I also realized that I was leaking my own narrative, abut two hundred characters
at a time. Instead of writing the stories of my experiences coherently, with my
own purpose and vision, I was just adding short quips to the collective
narrative. There's nothing wrong with adding to the collective, provided that
you're writing your own version, too.</p><p>So, I had to do the thing I said I wasn't going to do again: I had to build yet
another personal website. I didn't feel like getting a degree in hot new
frameworks, so I was originally going to go with Astro but Tailwind is just not
comfortable for me for a personal project, so I ended up using:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/docusaurus-plushie-banner-a60f7593abca1e3eef26a9afa244e4fb.jpeg" width="1500" height="500" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>... at least for now. I really want to play with Astro, as well as Fresh, but
the ecosystems around both are pretty Tailwind-heavy for the time being.</p><p>And for just a blog with a few static pages - Docusaurus is fine. I may even
bring back the docs and create some tutorials eventually, but the goal right now
is to just have a better professional presence.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Post</name>
            <uri>https://tinkertim.github.io</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="meta" term="meta"/>
    </entry>
</feed>