<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Tim Post's Blog Feed</title>
    <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Let's see what we have here ...</subtitle>
    <icon>https://tinkertim.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>Copyright 2023 Tim Post</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embrace The Bike Shed! Don't Get Hung Up On Community Software]]></title>
        <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/community-software</id>
        <link href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/community-software"/>
        <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's why you shouldn't fret over what software to use for commuinity hosting along with suggestions on what to consider instead.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>"What are we gonna use for <!-- -->[...]<!-- -->?"</em> is always the best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_triviality" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bike shed</a> question. I once had a coworker
who said the best color for the bike shed is <em>fire</em>. I agree, <em>usually</em>, but they can be useful
things in community dynamics. </p><p>There are two things that I really want you to know when it comes to initially fostering a new community:</p><ol><li>The organism, especially an online organism, <a href="https://www.azquotes.com/quote/968276" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">will do whatever it damn well pleases</a>. I'm not kidding.</li><li>Your choice of what software to use should be ultimately decided by users, after being initially
driven by user journey stories.</li></ol><p>If you understand both of those things, you might also say that this
seems a <em>little</em> over-simplified to you, and you're not wrong, but I'll do
my best to explain it in less than five minutes:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Community Growth" src="/assets/images/community-growth-og-dbbb34fbfdd675958563158124ceda57.png" width="2560" height="1440" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="drive-and-protect-growth-dont-try-to-control-it-too-much">Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much<a href="#drive-and-protect-growth-dont-try-to-control-it-too-much" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much" title="Direct link to Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much">​</a></h3><p>Wild idea: Let your community decide on the software it wants so that you're free to build
things that will delight them. Isn't that reflective of why you wanted a community in the
first place?</p><p>What if it was <em>just</em> your job to evaluate what's out there so you can rule any clear deal-breakers
out in conversations, and up to your community to decide on what it wants? For instance, let users
know that you require any vendor to be SOC-2 certified with all of the proper GDPR tooling. </p><p>I know what you're going to say: you'll need some kind of platform in order to even get that much
going, but that means we're now thinking on the same page! Use whatever works for <em>you</em> in the
very early instance, because it's critical that <em>you</em> have a constant presence in the community
early-on:</p><ul><li><p>You need to <strong>be there full time initially</strong> to deal with naysayers, spam, and have a voice with a
vision. You're the butler, the host, and the entertainment. </p></li><li><p>You then need to <strong>guard for question repitition</strong>. The minute you see it, launch a discussion
about where Q&amp;A should happen so that people don't get exhausted answering the same
questions over and over again. </p></li></ul><p>I've watched developer communities die slow agonzing deaths in Slack channels because founders
stopped at this very first step, and checked out until they could hire someone to do that. </p><p><strong><em>In my experience, "false starts" can be extremely toxic to future attempts fostering a community.</em></strong> Don't
begin this process until you're ready to have it on your plate and eat it, too. </p><p>Then, just like in a garden, you let the plants run the show while you establish new boundaries
and help move things around as needed to suppor their growth. That's the farthest I take the metaphor,
though; when you're talking details about nurturing communities you need real KPIs, not metaphors.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="your-initial-choice-should-be-very-driven-by-user-journey-stories">Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories<a href="#your-initial-choice-should-be-very-driven-by-user-journey-stories" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories" title="Direct link to Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories">​</a></h3><p>If you don't know what a user journey story is, you might be a little ahead of things by looking at
a community right now. A user journey story is a narrative that you create which, to the
best of your ability, reflects every detail of how people will find the thing you're building,
and why they'll want to use it. </p><p>Here's a fictitious ancient user story someone could have written about <a href="https://subversion.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Subversion</a>,
for example, back when it was rapidly-overtaking <a href="https://www.nongnu.org/cvs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CVS</a> as the version control system of
choice before Git:</p><blockquote><p><em>April is a senior developer at FuzzyWuzzy, and was tired of always e-mailing their
code updates in <code>.tgz</code> format even though the company used CVS, because it was so
difficult to use. They searched around and found Subversion was easier to use and
offered support beyond mailing lists.</em> </p></blockquote><p>So in this ancient example, we might, say, launch an IRC channel where we invite some
people to see if we can make some community magic happen, and use that channel to
coordinate launching something more useful and appropriate based on actual needs that
people communicate, not guesswork.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-tim-isnt-there-some-software-you-love-above-all-others">But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?<a href="#but-tim-isnt-there-some-software-you-love-above-all-others" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?" title="Direct link to But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?">​</a></h3><p>I have favorite wrenches, too, but I don't use them when I should be holding a lufa sponge,
you know?</p><p>Yes, you need to treat your community as something that has the same observability as any other
important thing - and there are thankfully great choices for that. There's also great community
platforms popping up all the time. </p><p>Your community will develop features of its own through process if you don't implement it
in software, so you might as well give them the largest seat at the table of what's being
used.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summing-it-up">Summing It Up:<a href="#summing-it-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summing It Up:" title="Direct link to Summing It Up:">​</a></h3><p>Don't get hung up on software if you want to start fostering a community around your
product. Instead, get busy working out all the ways you expect people to find your
product, determine some low-friction routes for folks using it to find eachother,
and be there to help them grow when <em>they're</em> ready. Just make sure they know the
criteria for an acceptable platform. </p><p>By doing it this way, you collaborate out of the gate and instill more trust, and the
optimal setup tends to find itself. Just make sure you're there to follow through,
be the face and voice, and executue on what they decide along with you.</p><p>Maybe four minutes. Okay it was probably five. But I hope you enjoyed reading!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Post</name>
            <uri>https://tinkertim.github.io</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="community-strategy" term="community-strategy"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I'm Thinking About Getting Edgy With]]></title>
        <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/uses-for-edge-functions</id>
        <link href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/uses-for-edge-functions"/>
        <updated>2023-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone seems to want to use edge functions, but nobody knows quite what to do with them. Here's my current list of things I want to build this year.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=edge+functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge functions</a> <sup><small>(<em>Google Link</em>)</small></sup>
are really appealing to me because the majority of web work that I do involves some
kind of documentation, which these days usually means using a static site generator
of some sort. These well-orchestrated SPAs are great, in fact this blg post is being
brought to you with one of them, but they're just that - static.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Functions" src="/assets/images/functions-og-00c9a935df1380693b6fe8e74d0e20b3.png" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>I used the Google link because the vendors are still figuring it out. This is all
still kinda new, which is neat (IMHO).</p><p>There are enough places that provide usable "freemium tier" edge functions, some
even complete with storage, that hobbyists and open-source enthisiasts like me
can build stuff and not need to pay a monthly bill for it. I might even package
a few I'm building around my own site, if I can think of a sensible way to "package"
the serverless part of it. </p><p>So without further rambling, here's my list in no real order other than recall:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="was-this-document-helpful-plugin-for-docusaurus">"Was this document helpful?" plugin for Docusaurus<a href="#was-this-document-helpful-plugin-for-docusaurus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Was this document helpful?&quot; plugin for Docusaurus" title="Direct link to &quot;Was this document helpful?&quot; plugin for Docusaurus">​</a></h3><p>I have no desire to implement comments or anything else that would require moderation,
but getting feedback about the relevancy and usefulness of all of your docs and
blog posts would be pretty super duper, right? </p><p>Edge functions are great at handling all of the rate limiting and other stuff you'd
want to implement server-side, as well as an API to get stats from it. Many of them
offer some kind of storage option on the same physical network to store responses.</p><p>The caveat here is, you may or may not be able to access local storage and dependency
resolution / loading could be an obstacle. Anyway, I'm kicking around the idea of
building it if I can do it in a portable way manageably.</p><p>I could probably get a V0 option for that done very quickly on Deno, but that kinda
marries using the plugin to using Deno Deploy or someone that resold it. Not ideal.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="my-devrel-discord-bot-box-awaitbot">My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)<a href="#my-devrel-discord-bot-box-awaitbot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)" title="Direct link to My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)">​</a></h3><p>It's easy to run user engagement events in Discord when you have droids helping you
manage it. Over the years, I've found that self-service contests work extremely well
for some of the same scenarios you might think about organizing a hackathon to boost.</p><p>The idea is, you let the user set their own definition of "done" for a project by
allowing the user to tell a bot that they're working on something, and then letting
the bot know when the project was done by including a link or a screen shot. </p><p>The bot can then (do a hundred other things) including giving the person a QR code to
get their prize shipped, and then someone from the company can reach out if warranted.</p><p>This project actually illustrates how you have to think about GDPR ahead of everything
else when you glue lots of stuff together like this, and there are indeed challenges
with the Discord API at scale, but I believe it's a project that will work.</p><p>I have a repo for this I'll dust off next month, maybe.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="client-side---edge-side-search">Client Side -&gt; Edge Side Search<a href="#client-side---edge-side-search" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Client Side -> Edge Side Search" title="Direct link to Client Side -> Edge Side Search">​</a></h3><p>For really big sites, it would be interesting if the compiled client-side index used for
client-side search could be just moved to an edge function upon deployment. It's not a
bad idea, though a little unconventional and prone to timing issues. </p><p>Third-party search options are getting harder to get working (and more expensive) as the
products evolve, so this might be a neat hybrid approach. </p><hr><p>Anyway, that's my list for the year, mostly around static sites. But I've seen people doing
all kinds of interesting things from fully-blown functional CRON systems to raw data pipes
to worker farms to others - and there's plenty of freemium options, so it's a fun thing to
play with.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Post</name>
            <uri>https://tinkertim.github.io</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="edge-functions" term="edge-functions"/>
        <category label="typescript" term="typescript"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Looking For A New Long-Term Adventure!]]></title>
        <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting</id>
        <link href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting"/>
        <updated>2023-04-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm winding down my contracting engagements in hope of getting full-time employment status again. I'd love any recommendations!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-some-good-news">First, some good news!<a href="#first-some-good-news" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First, some good news!" title="Direct link to First, some good news!">​</a></h2><p>I'm really thrilled that, after passing some relatively huge health
milestones, it's now rational for me to think long-term again. Long-term
survival is never a sure thing for anyone, but cancer survivors feel a lot
better every year after their fifth year of remission because even older
survival numbers go up and to the right afterward.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Adventure" src="/assets/images/adventure-og-f4b301e2c5f2aec45917a040444ab8e1.png" width="1280" height="720" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Being asked something like ...  <em>where do you see yourself in a few years?</em> in
an interview no longer summons existential angst, which is a huge deal for me.
I can rationally see myself building something long-term, not just contributing
where I can to short-term needs while I waited to see how things went. </p><p>I've filled in my time by doing some contract work to meet our minimum expenses,
which has led me to amazing experiences I couldn't possibly have had otherwise.
However, I want to contribute more than just content assignments; I'm not done
making my mark on DevRel. </p><p>I've been in language-agnostic roles for years; I helped to implement Stack Overflow's
now famous remote-first work culture for the community growth team, I have
oodles of management experience and I'm a pretty darn nice guy. I've also got
a <a href="/stack">pretty capable studio</a>. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="so-what-do-i-want-to-do">So, What do I want to do?<a href="#so-what-do-i-want-to-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?" title="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?">​</a></h2><p>I want to help mentor the next age of DevRel pros. I want to bring everything I have
learned from running the world's hugest developer community together with my love for
helping people find their own voice and confidence on their feet. I want to direct
content, sure, but I want to teach others <em>how</em> that process works. </p><p>I also sorely miss the art of community building and management. And, well, I miss
longer-term relationships in general, which feels a bit lacking when you're just
an outside contractor.  </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-do-i-want-out-of-it">What do I want out of it?<a href="#what-do-i-want-out-of-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What do I want out of it?" title="Direct link to What do I want out of it?">​</a></h2><p>What I need from an employer:</p><ul><li>Remote-first culture</li><li>Flexible time. For tons of reasons.</li><li>Insurance that isn't a pain in the ass.</li><li>Rapid / fast-pace is great, if we keep it to 50-ish hour weeks.</li><li>Some kind of PTO program.</li><li>Commitment to a long-term DevRel program. I can be a one-person band,
but my goal is to build and lead a team with actually different people.</li></ul><p>As long as I can take breaks during the day and limit travel to a few times during
the year, my disability needs are met.  </p><p>Do you know someone? Please send them to me, or me to them!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Post</name>
            <uri>https://tinkertim.github.io</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="job" term="job"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Site! Again!]]></title>
        <id>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</id>
        <link href="https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2023-03-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've resisted having and maintaining a personal website, but events of late reminded me of the value of having my own content on my own domain.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you
spend creating content on other people's platforms? I thought about it quite a
bit when it was touch-and-go if Twitter would stabilize again, and in all
fairness, that's still mostly the case.</p><p>I also realized that I was leaking my own narrative, abut two hundred characters
at a time. Instead of writing the stories of my experiences coherently, with my
own purpose and vision, I was just adding short quips to the collective
narrative. There's nothing wrong with adding to the collective, provided that
you're writing your own version, too.</p><p>So, I had to do the thing I said I wasn't going to do again: I had to build yet
another personal website. I didn't feel like getting a degree in hot new
frameworks, so I was originally going to go with Astro but Tailwind is just not
comfortable for me for a personal project, so I ended up using:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/docusaurus-plushie-banner-a60f7593abca1e3eef26a9afa244e4fb.jpeg" width="1500" height="500" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>... at least for now. I really want to play with Astro, as well as Fresh, but
the ecosystems around both are pretty Tailwind-heavy for the time being.</p><p>And for just a blog with a few static pages - Docusaurus is fine. I may even
bring back the docs and create some tutorials eventually, but the goal right now
is to just have a better professional presence.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Post</name>
            <uri>https://tinkertim.github.io</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="website-meta" term="website-meta"/>
    </entry>
</feed>