<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Tim Post's Website Blog</title>
        <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Tim Post's Website Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm Looking For A New Long-Term Adventure!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I'm winding down my contracting engagements in hope of getting full-time employment status again. I'd love any recommendations!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-some-good-news">First, some good news!<a href="#first-some-good-news" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First, some good news!" title="Direct link to First, some good news!">​</a></h2><p>I'm really thrilled that, after passing some relatively huge health
milestones, it's now rational for me to think long-term again. Long-term
survival is never a sure thing for anyone, but cancer survivors feel a lot
better every year after their fifth year of remission because even older
survival numbers go up and to the right afterward.</p><p>Being asked something like ...  <em>where do you see yourself in a few years?</em> in
an interview no longer summons existential angst, which is a huge deal for me.
I can rationally see myself building something long-term, not just contributing
where I can to short-term needs while I waited to see how things went. </p><p>I've filled in my time by doing some contract work to meet our minimum expenses,
which has led me to amazing experiences I couldn't possibly have had otherwise.
However, I want to contribute more than just content assignments; I'm not done
making my mark on DevRel. </p><p>I've been in language-agnostic roles for years; I helped to implement Stack Overflow's
now famous remote-first work culture for the community growth team, I have
oodles of management experience and I'm a pretty darn nice guy. I've also got
a <a href="/stack">pretty capable studio</a>. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="so-what-do-i-want-to-do">So, What do I want to do?<a href="#so-what-do-i-want-to-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?" title="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?">​</a></h2><p>I want to help mentor the next age of DevRel pros. I want to bring everything I have
learned from running the world's hugest developer community together with my love for
helping people find their own voice and confidence on their feet. I want to direct
content, sure, but I want to teach others <em>how</em> that process works. </p><p>I also sorely miss the art of community building and management. And, well, I miss
longer-term relationships in general, which feels a bit lacking when you're just
an outside contractor.  </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-do-i-want-out-of-it">What do I want out of it?<a href="#what-do-i-want-out-of-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What do I want out of it?" title="Direct link to What do I want out of it?">​</a></h2><p>What I need from an employer:</p><ul><li>Remote-first culture</li><li>Flexible time. For tons of reasons.</li><li>Insurance that isn't a pain in the ass.</li><li>Rapid / fast-pace is great, if we keep it to 50-ish hour weeks.</li><li>Some kind of PTO program.</li><li>Commitment to a long-term DevRel program. I can be a one-person band,
but my goal is to build and lead a team with actually different people.</li></ul><p>As long as I can take breaks during the day and limit travel to a few times during
the year, my disability needs are met.  </p><p>Do you know someone? Please send them to me, or me to them!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>meta</category>
            <category>job</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Site! Again!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you
spend creating content on other people's platforms? I thought about it quite a
bit when it was touch-and-go if Twitter would stabilize again, and in all
fairness, that's still mostly the case.</p><p>I also realized that I was leaking my own narrative, abut two hundred characters
at a time. Instead of writing the stories of my experiences coherently, with my
own purpose and vision, I was just adding short quips to the collective
narrative. There's nothing wrong with adding to the collective, provided that
you're writing your own version, too.</p><p>So, I had to do the thing I said I wasn't going to do again: I had to build yet
another personal website. I didn't feel like getting a degree in hot new
frameworks, so I was originally going to go with Astro but Tailwind is just not
comfortable for me for a personal project, so I ended up using:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/docusaurus-plushie-banner-a60f7593abca1e3eef26a9afa244e4fb.jpeg" width="1500" height="500" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>... at least for now. I really want to play with Astro, as well as Fresh, but
the ecosystems around both are pretty Tailwind-heavy for the time being.</p><p>And for just a blog with a few static pages - Docusaurus is fine. I may even
bring back the docs and create some tutorials eventually, but the goal right now
is to just have a better professional presence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>meta</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>