<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Tim Post's Blog Feed</title>
        <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Let's see what we have here ...</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 2023 Tim Post</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Stop Polluting Your GA4 Engagement Data "Almost" Quickly]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/ga4-internal-filtering</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/ga4-internal-filtering</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Google Analytics 4 has the ability to keep your own use from polluting your engagement data. Surprisingly, this functionality is hard-to-find. Here's how!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most meaningful metrics for a documentation site is how long
the average "engaged" session lasts. Put simply, how much time people stay
on various segments of your site could mean really good, or even potentially
not-so-good things, so you really want that number to be accurate.</p><p>Your team's early use of the site while setting up often pollutes
this engagement data at a really critical time; here's a tutorial on how to avoid
that!</p><a href="/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/internal-filtering-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Imagine 'complicated' and then take away reason and accountability" alt="Creative depiction of a need to filter engagement data"></a><p>To get the most out of this short tutorial, make sure you have the IP addresses that
your own use of your sites originates from handy, and about ten minutes of time. In fact,
you'll probably want to set up rules for additional remote workers or even other offices
that might interact with the sites like users would. </p><p>Depending on how you have Analytics configured (I suggest using Google Tag
Manager; this tutorial assumes you are too), you probably don't load Analytics
code while your site is running in development or staging mode. </p><p>This means you won't pollute your data by testing and doing development work, but
tag manager <em>will</em> always hoist Analytics code when the site is in production mode,
causing anything you do to count like you were a user. This isn't ideal, to say the
least, and hard-coded IP filter hacks in your site's source code really smells. </p><p>Here's how to deal with it using GA alone, step by step:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1-define-an-internal-traffic_type-for-the-google-tag">Step 1: Define An "internal" <code>traffic_type</code> For The Google Tag:<a href="#step-1-define-an-internal-traffic_type-for-the-google-tag" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to step-1-define-an-internal-traffic_type-for-the-google-tag" title="Direct link to step-1-define-an-internal-traffic_type-for-the-google-tag">​</a></h3><p>This, unfortunately, entails a lot of clicks. First, go to the Admin
section of analytics:</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-1.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Next, click on "Data Streams" and click on the site you want to modify
on the right:</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-2.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Then, scroll down to the "Google Tag" settings part of the site. Click on
that:</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-3.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Then click on "Configure Tag Settings":</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-4.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Once you've done that, click on "Show All" (I <em>told</em> you this was hidden):</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-5.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Next, click on "Define Internal Traffic":</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-6.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Finally! Create a new location, name it meainingfully, and provide IP addresses
individually, or with a netmask (like if you want a whole /24 ignored). <strong>Make
absolutely sure that you save it! Note the save button in the top-right:</strong></p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-7.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>PHEW. Need some coffee? Maybe you should go get some coffee or stretch out. I
kid really, it's not that bad unless you're a product manager.  </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2-the-filter-or-testing-mode">Step 2: The Filter Or Testing Mode<a href="#step-2-the-filter-or-testing-mode" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2: The Filter Or Testing Mode" title="Direct link to Step 2: The Filter Or Testing Mode">​</a></h3><p>This is the easy part. Go back to the main admin route and this time, click on the
"Data Settings" icon, expand the little menu, and then click on the "Filters" link. You
will see that Google so thoughtfully created the filter for you, even though they don't
show you this functionality when you set it up.</p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-8.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><p>Click on the filter and enable it. Make sure you save! You can set it to testing if you
want, but that still makes reporting noisy unless you filter it out later, so I recommend
just turning it off right away. </p><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/ga4-internal-filtering/screenshot-9.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Screenshot" alt="Supplementary Screenshot"><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-3-wait-a-few-hours-then-test">Step 3: Wait A Few Hours, Then Test<a href="#step-3-wait-a-few-hours-then-test" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 3: Wait A Few Hours, Then Test" title="Direct link to Step 3: Wait A Few Hours, Then Test">​</a></h3><p>Google says it can take a while for changes to be applied to all recent data (which seems
to be the case in my experience), but you will notice that it almost immediately stops all
logging from the addresses you provided. Confirm this by hitting production links from a
location that you squelched.</p><p>Initially, even the "live" view stopped registering my visists from internally-flagged IPs,
but this flickered as changes were applied. I'll update this post in several weeks once enough
time has passed and note what the end behavior looks like, if it differs from what Google says
to expect. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="closing">Closing<a href="#closing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Closing" title="Direct link to Closing">​</a></h3><p>I think Google should simplify this process, including providing a better tool to
look up your own IP address. This is a great example use case for filters in general, and
you probably noticed there's a lot more that you can do with them. </p><p>This easy enough to add to your setup checklist, now that you know where it lives. I hope you
found this useful!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>ga4</category>
            <category>tutorial</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, You Need A Community Newsletter. Here's Some Inspiration!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/you-need-a-community-newsletter</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/you-need-a-community-newsletter</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A newsletter is an essential tool for community building. I talk about ideas for content you can include in them, especially when you don't have much to start with.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to be extremely anti-email. I still am, personally, but I no longer
squint and try to point at my nose with my lips when someone mentions an email
drip campaign where software developers are the target audience. </p><p>I think I'm also safe in saying that many people expect that they'll be subscribed
to <em>some</em> kind of list when they join a new community, with an easy one-link / one-click
way to opt-out, does that sound about right?</p><a href="/blog/you-need-a-community-newsletter/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/you-need-a-community-newsletter/newsletter-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="As long as you're respectful of recipient's time and deliver real value, a community newsletter can be an important early tool." alt="Creative depiction of an electronic newsletter"></a><p>I guess that means there's no good excuse for not having a newsletter for your
online community. Well, maybe there is one excuse: not knowing what to write about. I can help
there; let's talk about a bunch of stuff you can do when you really don't have great witty
ideas to send out.</p><p>How you structure your community digest is up to you. Once a community reaches more than 50
people, I like to have a <em>community specific</em> newsletter that I launch just for community-related
updates. It's a great way to focus engagement on things in an easy, relaxed way and a great way
to keep community satisfaction high.</p><p>I try to keep community newsletters speific to <em>community</em> news, even though that's frequently going
to overlap with some product news, I like to keep the product stuff to the primary newsletter that
the investors and everyone else gets. </p><p>Here's some ideas for what can go in your community newsletter perennially, or just as-needed when you
don't have enough other content to really justify sending something out:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="spotlight-heroes--welcome-nominations">Spotlight Heroes &amp; Welcome Nominations<a href="#spotlight-heroes--welcome-nominations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Spotlight Heroes &amp; Welcome Nominations" title="Direct link to Spotlight Heroes &amp; Welcome Nominations">​</a></h3><p>Set a high threshold for this so it's a big deal when someone crosses it, but make sure you keep track
of the effort people are putting in, and when they really crush something or go above and beyond, shine
a light on them by telling the story to everyone else.</p><p>Reach out to the person in advance because this kind of spotlight can be uncomfortable for<br>
<!-- -->some, and make sure people know you are interested in hearing about other instances that should
be celebrated. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="leak-some-inside-info">"Leak" Some Inside Info<a href="#leak-some-inside-info" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Leak&quot; Some Inside Info" title="Direct link to &quot;Leak&quot; Some Inside Info">​</a></h3><p>Everyone loves an inside scoop. Could your product team occasionally provide some screen shots or
other teasers so your community occasionally gets early access? It's a great way to get early feedback,
make people feel special, and make sure there's something interesting for them to read about. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="interview-a-developer-or-pm">Interview A Developer Or PM<a href="#interview-a-developer-or-pm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Interview A Developer Or PM" title="Direct link to Interview A Developer Or PM">​</a></h3><p>I once maintained a newsletter where in each issue, we would ask the community to send some questions for
one of our product managers as we published the answers to the questions posted the previous week. This was
a great two-way conduit for our product team with me as a sort of filter and go-between and was a favorite
part of the newsletter.</p><p>You might find that, upon asking around, other employees might have great insights or topics to share with your
community as employees see that other interviews are received positively and appreciated. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="adopt-a-pr">Adopt A PR<a href="#adopt-a-pr" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Adopt A PR" title="Direct link to Adopt A PR">​</a></h3><p>Some pull requests represent a great deal of work and care, but need someone else to care about them a little
before they can be accepted. It's super helpful, extremely welcoming, and very empowering to the whole community.</p><p>It's helpful if you organize outreach to receive nominations for these, with self-nominations being explicitly
encouraged. Similarly, offer to help maintainers of projects that your community cares about find new contributors,
or even new maintainers entirely if necessary.</p><p>A little facilitating can get you a lot of goodwill. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="community-blog-posts--call-for-submissions">Community Blog Posts &amp; Call For Submissions<a href="#community-blog-posts--call-for-submissions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Community Blog Posts &amp; Call For Submissions" title="Direct link to Community Blog Posts &amp; Call For Submissions">​</a></h3><p>It's great when people who don't work at your company write about your product. Make sure your community knows you'll
syndicate posts they write and tell you about in your main newsletter, even if they aren't 100% flattering. It's also
great if you reach out to community authors when you have paid writing work available.</p><p>Never offer to pay people with exposure, but giving exposure when they've already done something awesome is
a great thing to do. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hidden-prizes">Hidden Prizes<a href="#hidden-prizes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hidden Prizes" title="Direct link to Hidden Prizes">​</a></h3><p>Once in a while, deliver some completely spontaneous and random fun. Give stickers for those that participate in a "caption this"
contest, or something else that just lets people be happy they opened your email. Make a meme or two. Feature your own poorly-drawn
comic strip, as long as it's relevant to the community. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="let-it-become-community-led">Let It Become Community-led<a href="#let-it-become-community-led" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Let It Become Community-led" title="Direct link to Let It Become Community-led">​</a></h3><p>These are just ideas. The best newsletter is the one you produce based on feedback from your community. What matters is
that you send it, send it consistently, and make sure you put some real attention toward making each issue valuable.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>community-growth</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How To Set Inclusive Priorities For Communities]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/explaining-priorities-improves-inclusion</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/explaining-priorities-improves-inclusion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Writing about priorities is more effective and inclusive when approached from a results-oriented perspective. Here's how to do that easily!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm not sure who was the first person to speak the following sacred funnel
wisdom text, or even precisely how it was first conveyed, but it sounded
something a lot like this:</p><blockquote><p>When troubleshooting funnels, never look for output at the end
of the funnel unless that's actually the next stage of the funnel.</p></blockquote><p>Some of the most difficult funnels to "debug" are the ones that require busy
people to devote their full attention to something that you want to show them,
or have them participate in.</p><a href="/blog/explaining-priorities-improves-inclusion/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/explaining-priorities-improves-inclusion/priorities-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="If deadlines seem arbitrary, neurodivergent people often watch as they fly right by. Here are thoughts on how and when to communicate priorities more effectively AND inclusively." alt="Why Some Priorities Should Be Explained (designer text)"></a><p>And this, my colleagues, is because it's sometimes <em>really</em> tricky to get other
people to share your sense for how important something is, even when they say it is.
Whether it's finally getting someone to schedule a demo or getting people to attend
a webinar, we generally do a not-great job of helping them know why their life just
won't be as great if they deprioritize our thing. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="humans-are-often-unaware-of-how-they-re--prioritize">Humans Are Often Unaware Of How They (re-) Prioritize.<a href="#humans-are-often-unaware-of-how-they-re--prioritize" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Humans Are Often Unaware Of How They (re-) Prioritize." title="Direct link to Humans Are Often Unaware Of How They (re-) Prioritize.">​</a></h3><p>The <code>tl;dr</code> of it is simply that people don't prioritize things the same way, and since
our organic brains do it with lots of <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/11227809/why-is-processing-a-sorted-array-faster-than-processing-an-unsorted-array" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">branch prediction</a>,
people aren't always cognizant when they de-prioritize a task or even their rationalization
for why something else is important; they do it because their brain <em>knew</em> it could rationalize
it, and sent them some dopamine just to make them feel a-okay about your hackathon entry deadline
flying right by. </p><p>If they knew that the order with their trophy would get all screwed up because they weren't
on the correct spreadsheet in time, they might not have decided to play another round of Mario
Kart.</p><p>Prioritization among neurodivergent folks can take on even more levels, and understanding
priorities differently is one of the biggest causes of spats in open source communities. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="we-often-stink-when-it-comes-to-calling-others-to-action">We Often Stink When It Comes To Calling Others To Action<a href="#we-often-stink-when-it-comes-to-calling-others-to-action" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to We Often Stink When It Comes To Calling Others To Action" title="Direct link to We Often Stink When It Comes To Calling Others To Action">​</a></h3><p>How we sort consequences from "scariest thing ever" to "meh" has a lot to do with what we
tend to let go of when we need to allocate more focus to a single task. If we think that
the deadline for <!-- -->[X]<!-- --> is arbitrary, some organic CPUs will de-prioritize it in the background
without even telling the user, causing them to forget it entirely.</p><p>Getting to the WIIFM quickly is critical if you want to get something on people's radar,
especially people that have highly interrupt-driven jobs. But that's not always enough
to make them appropriately cognizant of keeping the plate high enough in the air. WIIFM
is an acronym for <em>"What's In It For Me?"</em>, if you didn't know.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="to-convey-importance-consider-stating-the-results-first">To Convey Importance, Consider Stating The Results First<a href="#to-convey-importance-consider-stating-the-results-first" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to To Convey Importance, Consider Stating The Results First" title="Direct link to To Convey Importance, Consider Stating The Results First">​</a></h3><p>Consider the following two sentences:</p><blockquote><p><em>"Please send your bio no later than August 15."</em></p></blockquote><p>And:</p><blockquote><p><em>"If you want your name printed on the prize, we need your bio by August 15."</em></p></blockquote><p>Both sentences are professional. The top sentence is laconic and polite, but it's also not
very effective. People <em>will</em> wait until days before the event to send it in because they
aren't thinking about contest fulfillment. </p><p>The second sentence starts with a preposition, which helps snap out of someone glazing
over the text. It doesn't begin with Please because the word often causes people's
eyes to glaze back over. We're polite, but not easily scrolled past. </p><p>Finally, the sentence conveys a real consequence which will tie not getting the bio in time
to a sense of disappointment, making it WAY less likely to get optimized away by the human organic
compiler. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="it-matters-in-feedback-too">It Matters In Feedback, Too!<a href="#it-matters-in-feedback-too" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to It Matters In Feedback, Too!" title="Direct link to It Matters In Feedback, Too!">​</a></h3><p>Here are two more sentences, but coming from a user from a perspective of wanting a new
feature:</p><blockquote><p><em>"Please implement raw markdown mode."</em></p></blockquote><p>Great. Straight. To the point, but it's not going to get the product team to alter the way
they currently have this prioritized, or give any indication of what would happen if they
waited 120 days or more to do it. </p><blockquote><p><em>"When raw markdown is enabled, I can clear out our queue faster and get more of my team on board with adopting <!-- -->[product]<!-- -->."</em></p></blockquote><p>This is better for the same reasons that we saw in the first example, but you've effectively:</p><ul><li>Broke the reader out of "scroll mode"</li><li>Described an ideal outcome in a self-empowering way</li></ul><p>The scenario is just an example, and you can't always use titles in this way, but you get
the general idea. </p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="mutually-shared-priorities-result-in-healthier-communities">Mutually-shared Priorities Result In Healthier Communities<a href="#mutually-shared-priorities-result-in-healthier-communities" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Mutually-shared Priorities Result In Healthier Communities" title="Direct link to Mutually-shared Priorities Result In Healthier Communities">​</a></h3><p>This really goes without saying, but you'd be surprised how much paying attention to this when
crafting CTAs can improve your engagemnt across the board: internal to external, and external
to internal. It helps neurodivergent people feel valued and considered, and results in better
overall communication.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>community-strategy</category>
            <category>community-growth</category>
            <category>inclusive-leadership</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embrace The Bike Shed! Don't Get Hung Up On Community Software]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/community-software</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/community-software</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Here's why you shouldn't fret over what software to use for commuinity hosting along with suggestions on what to consider instead.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>"What are we gonna use for <!-- -->[...]<!-- -->?"</em> is always the best <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_triviality" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bike shed</a> question. I once had a coworker
who said the best color for the bike shed is <em>fire</em>. I agree, <em>usually</em>, but they can be useful
things in community dynamics. </p><p>There are two things that I really want you to know when it comes to initially fostering a new community:</p><ol><li>The organism, especially an online organism, <a href="https://www.azquotes.com/quote/968276" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">will do whatever it damn well pleases</a>. I'm not kidding.</li><li>Your choice of what software to use should be ultimately decided by users, after being initially
driven by user journey stories.</li></ol><p>If you understand both of those things, you might also say that this
seems a <em>little</em> over-simplified to you, and you're not wrong, but I'll do
my best to explain it in less than five minutes:</p><a href="/blog/community-software/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/community-software/community-growth-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" title="Communities Like Making Their Own Decisions" alt="Artwork representing a community"></a><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="drive-and-protect-growth-dont-try-to-control-it-too-much">Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much<a href="#drive-and-protect-growth-dont-try-to-control-it-too-much" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much" title="Direct link to Drive And Protect Growth; Don't Try To Control It Too Much">​</a></h3><p>Wild idea: Let your community decide on the software it wants so that you're free to build
things that will delight them. Isn't that reflective of why you wanted a community in the
first place?</p><p>What if it was <em>just</em> your job to evaluate what's out there so you can rule any clear deal-breakers
out in conversations, and up to your community to decide on what it wants? For instance, let users
know that you require any vendor to be SOC-2 certified with all of the proper GDPR tooling. </p><p>I know what you're going to say: you'll need some kind of platform in order to even get that much
going, but that means we're now thinking on the same page! Use whatever works for <em>you</em> in the
very early instance, because it's critical that <em>you</em> have a constant presence in the community
early-on:</p><ul><li><p>You need to <strong>be there full time initially</strong> to deal with naysayers, spam, and have a voice with a
vision. You're the butler, the host, and the entertainment. </p></li><li><p>You then need to <strong>guard for question repitition</strong>. The minute you see it, launch a discussion
about where Q&amp;A should happen so that people don't get exhausted answering the same
questions over and over again. </p></li></ul><p>I've watched developer communities die slow agonzing deaths in Slack channels because founders
stopped at this very first step, and checked out until they could hire someone to do that. </p><p><strong><em>In my experience, "false starts" can be extremely toxic to future attempts fostering a community.</em></strong> Don't
begin this process until you're ready to have it on your plate and eat it, too. </p><p>Then, just like in a garden, you let the plants run the show while you establish new boundaries
and help move things around as needed to suppor their growth. That's the farthest I take the metaphor,
though; when you're talking details about nurturing communities you need real KPIs, not metaphors.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="your-initial-choice-should-be-very-driven-by-user-journey-stories">Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories<a href="#your-initial-choice-should-be-very-driven-by-user-journey-stories" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories" title="Direct link to Your Initial Choice Should Be Very Driven By User Journey Stories">​</a></h3><p>If you don't know what a user journey story is, you might be a little ahead of things by looking at
a community right now. A user journey story is a narrative that you create which, to the
best of your ability, reflects every detail of how people will find the thing you're building,
and why they'll want to use it. </p><p>Here's a fictitious ancient user story someone could have written about <a href="https://subversion.apache.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Subversion</a>,
for example, back when it was rapidly-overtaking <a href="https://www.nongnu.org/cvs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CVS</a> as the version control system of
choice before Git:</p><blockquote><p><em>April is a senior developer at FuzzyWuzzy, and was tired of always e-mailing their
code updates in <code>.tgz</code> format even though the company used CVS, because it was so
difficult to use. They searched around and found Subversion was easier to use and
offered support beyond mailing lists.</em> </p></blockquote><p>So in this ancient example, we might, say, launch an IRC channel where we invite some
people to see if we can make some community magic happen, and use that channel to
coordinate launching something more useful and appropriate based on actual needs that
people communicate, not guesswork.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-tim-isnt-there-some-software-you-love-above-all-others">But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?<a href="#but-tim-isnt-there-some-software-you-love-above-all-others" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?" title="Direct link to But, Tim, Isn't There Some Software You Love Above All Others?">​</a></h3><p>I have favorite wrenches, too, but I don't use them when I should be holding a lufa sponge,
you know?</p><p>Yes, you need to treat your community as something that has the same observability as any other
important thing - and there are thankfully great choices for that. There's also great community
platforms popping up all the time. </p><p>Your community will develop features of its own through process if you don't implement it
in software, so you might as well give them the largest seat at the table of what's being
used.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="summing-it-up">Summing It Up:<a href="#summing-it-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summing It Up:" title="Direct link to Summing It Up:">​</a></h3><p>Don't get hung up on software if you want to start fostering a community around your
product. Instead, get busy working out all the ways you expect people to find your
product, determine some low-friction routes for folks using it to find eachother,
and be there to help them grow when <em>they're</em> ready. Just make sure they know the
criteria for an acceptable platform. </p><p>By doing it this way, you collaborate out of the gate and instill more trust, and the
optimal setup tends to find itself. Just make sure you're there to follow through,
be the face and voice, and executue on what they decide along with you.</p><p>Maybe four minutes. Okay it was probably five. But I hope you enjoyed reading!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>community-strategy</category>
            <category>community-growth</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Things I'm Thinking About Getting Edgy With]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/uses-for-edge-functions</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/uses-for-edge-functions</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Everyone seems to want to use edge functions, but nobody knows quite what to do with them. Here's my current list of things I want to build this year.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=edge+functions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Edge functions</a> <sup><small>(<em>Google Link</em>)</small></sup>
are really appealing to me because the majority of web work that I do involves some
kind of documentation, which these days usually means using a static site generator
of some sort. These well-orchestrated SPAs are great, in fact this blg post is being
brought to you with one of them, but they're just that - static.</p><a href="/blog/uses-for-edge-functions/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/uses-for-edge-functions/functions-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" alt="Artwork representing functions" title="Edge functions are all the rage. Good news is, they're actually useful, too!"></a><p>I used the Google link because the vendors are still figuring it out. This is all
still kinda new, which is neat (IMHO).</p><p>There are enough places that provide usable "freemium tier" edge functions, some
even complete with storage, that hobbyists and open-source enthisiasts like me
can build stuff and not need to pay a monthly bill for it. I might even package
a few I'm building around my own site, if I can think of a sensible way to "package"
the serverless part of it. </p><p>So without further rambling, here's my list in no real order other than recall:</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="was-this-document-helpful-plugin-for-docusaurus">"Was this document helpful?" plugin for Docusaurus<a href="#was-this-document-helpful-plugin-for-docusaurus" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Was this document helpful?&quot; plugin for Docusaurus" title="Direct link to &quot;Was this document helpful?&quot; plugin for Docusaurus">​</a></h3><p>I have no desire to implement comments or anything else that would require moderation,
but getting feedback about the relevancy and usefulness of all of your docs and
blog posts would be pretty super duper, right? </p><p>Edge functions are great at handling all of the rate limiting and other stuff you'd
want to implement server-side, as well as an API to get stats from it. Many of them
offer some kind of storage option on the same physical network to store responses.</p><p>The caveat here is, you may or may not be able to access local storage and dependency
resolution / loading could be an obstacle. Anyway, I'm kicking around the idea of
building it if I can do it in a portable way manageably.</p><p>I could probably get a V0 option for that done very quickly on Deno, but that kinda
marries using the plugin to using Deno Deploy or someone that resold it. Not ideal.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="my-devrel-discord-bot-box-awaitbot">My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)<a href="#my-devrel-discord-bot-box-awaitbot" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)" title="Direct link to My DevRel Discord Bot Box (Awaitbot)">​</a></h3><p>It's easy to run user engagement events in Discord when you have droids helping you
manage it. Over the years, I've found that self-service contests work extremely well
for some of the same scenarios you might think about organizing a hackathon to boost.</p><p>The idea is, you let the user set their own definition of "done" for a project by
allowing the user to tell a bot that they're working on something, and then letting
the bot know when the project was done by including a link or a screen shot. </p><p>The bot can then (do a hundred other things) including giving the person a QR code to
get their prize shipped, and then someone from the company can reach out if warranted.</p><p>This project actually illustrates how you have to think about GDPR ahead of everything
else when you glue lots of stuff together like this, and there are indeed challenges
with the Discord API at scale, but I believe it's a project that will work.</p><p>I have a repo for this I'll dust off next month, maybe.</p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="client-side---edge-side-search">Client Side -&gt; Edge Side Search<a href="#client-side---edge-side-search" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Client Side -> Edge Side Search" title="Direct link to Client Side -> Edge Side Search">​</a></h3><p>For really big sites, it would be interesting if the compiled client-side index used for
client-side search could be just moved to an edge function upon deployment. It's not a
bad idea, though a little unconventional and prone to timing issues. </p><p>Third-party search options are getting harder to get working (and more expensive) as the
products evolve, so this might be a neat hybrid approach. </p><hr><p>Anyway, that's my list for the year, mostly around static sites. But I've seen people doing
all kinds of interesting things from fully-blown functional CRON systems to raw data pipes
to worker farms to others - and there's plenty of freemium options, so it's a fun thing to
play with.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>edge-functions</category>
            <category>typescript</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm Looking For A New Long-Term Adventure!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/job-hunting</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I'm winding down my contracting engagements in hope of getting full-time employment status again. I'd love any recommendations!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="first-some-good-news">First, some good news!<a href="#first-some-good-news" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to First, some good news!" title="Direct link to First, some good news!">​</a></h2><p>I'm really thrilled that, after passing some relatively huge health
milestones, it's now rational for me to think long-term again. Long-term
survival is never a sure thing for anyone, but cancer survivors feel a lot
better every year after their fifth year of remission because even older
survival numbers go up and to the right afterward.</p><a href="/blog/job-hunting/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/job-hunting/adventure-og.png" class="blogImage img_ev3q" alt="Artwork representing a new adventure" title="Never fun, but always exciting!"></a><p>Being asked something like ...  <em>where do you see yourself in a few years?</em> in
an interview no longer summons existential angst, which is a huge deal for me.
I can rationally see myself building something long-term, not just contributing
where I can to short-term needs while I waited to see how things went. </p><p>I've filled in my time by doing some contract work to meet our minimum expenses,
which has led me to amazing experiences I couldn't possibly have had otherwise.
However, I want to contribute more than just content assignments; I'm not done
making my mark on DevRel. </p><p>I've been in language-agnostic roles for years; I helped to implement Stack Overflow's
now famous remote-first work culture for the community growth team, I have
oodles of management experience and I'm a pretty darn nice guy. I've also got
a <a href="/stack/">pretty capable studio</a>. </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="so-what-do-i-want-to-do">So, What do I want to do?<a href="#so-what-do-i-want-to-do" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?" title="Direct link to So, What do I want to do?">​</a></h2><p>I want to help mentor the next age of DevRel pros. I want to bring everything I have
learned from running the world's hugest developer community together with my love for
helping people find their own voice and confidence on their feet. I want to direct
content, sure, but I want to teach others <em>how</em> that process works. </p><p>I also sorely miss the art of community building and management. And, well, I miss
longer-term relationships in general, which feels a bit lacking when you're just
an outside contractor.  </p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-do-i-want-out-of-it">What do I want out of it?<a href="#what-do-i-want-out-of-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What do I want out of it?" title="Direct link to What do I want out of it?">​</a></h2><p>What I need from an employer:</p><ul><li>Remote-first culture</li><li>Flexible time. For tons of reasons.</li><li>Insurance that isn't a pain in the ass.</li><li>Rapid / fast-pace is great, if we keep it to 50-ish hour weeks.</li><li>Some kind of PTO program.</li><li>Commitment to a long-term DevRel program. I can be a one-person band,
but my goal is to build and lead a team with actually different people.</li></ul><p>As long as I can take breaks during the day and limit travel to a few times during
the year, my disability needs are met.  </p><p>Do you know someone? Please send them to me, or me to them!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>job</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Site! Again!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I've resisted having and maintaining a personal website, but events of late reminded me of the value of having my own content on my own domain.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about how much time you
spend creating content on other people's platforms? I thought about it quite a
bit when it was touch-and-go if Twitter would stabilize again, and in all
fairness, that's still mostly the case.</p><p>I also realized that I was leaking my own narrative, abut two hundred characters
at a time. Instead of writing the stories of my experiences coherently, with my
own purpose and vision, I was just adding short quips to the collective
narrative. There's nothing wrong with adding to the collective, provided that
you're writing your own version, too.</p><p>So, I had to do the thing I said I wasn't going to do again: I had to build yet
another personal website. I didn't feel like getting a degree in hot new
frameworks, so I was originally going to go with Astro but Tailwind is just not
comfortable for me for a personal project, so I ended up using:</p><a href="/blog/welcome/"><img loading="lazy" src="/img/blog/welcome/docusaurus-plushie-banner.jpeg" class="blogImage img_ev3q" alt="Docusaurus Plushies" title="Somehow, I always pick Docusaurus when I need to get shit done."></a><p>... at least for now. I really want to play with Astro, as well as Fresh, but
the ecosystems around both are pretty Tailwind-heavy for the time being.</p><p>And for just a blog with a few static pages - Docusaurus is fine. I may even
bring back the docs and create some tutorials eventually, but the goal right now
is to just have a better professional presence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>website-meta</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>