<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Tim Post Blog</title>
        <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Tim Post Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Site! Again!]]></title>
            <link>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://tinkertim.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did the whole Twitter shakeup make you stop and think about
how much time you spend creating content on other people's
platforms? I thought about it quite a bit when it was touch-and-go
if Twitter would stabilize again, and in all fairness, that's still
mostly the case.</p><p>I also realized that I was leaking my own narrative, abut two hundred
characters at a time. Instead of writing the stories of my experiences
coherently, with my own purpose and vision, I was just adding short
quips to the collective narrative. There's nothing wrong with adding to
the collective, provided that you're writing your own version, too.</p><p>So, I had to do the thing I said I wasn't going to do again: I had to build
yet another personal website. I didn't feel like getting a degree in
hot new frameworks, so I was originally going to go with Astro but Tailwind
is just not comfortable for me for a personal project, so I ended up using:</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/docusaurus-plushie-banner-a60f7593abca1e3eef26a9afa244e4fb.jpeg" width="1500" height="500" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>... at least for now. I really want to play with Astro, as well as Fresh,
but the ecosystems around both are pretty Tailwind-heavy for the time being.</p><p>And for just a blog with a few static pages - Docusaurus is fine. I may even
bring back the docs and create some tutorials eventually, but the goal right now is to just have a better professional presence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>meta</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>